Guide to the Paul van Tassel Hedden Papers, 1951-1960
Hedden, Paul van Tassel papers, 1951-1960
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Paul van Tassel Hedden papers, 1951-1960
2532
Paul van Tassel Hedden.
4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, legislative bills, pamphlets, surveys, photographs, maps, and other items.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers consist mainly of correspondence, reports, legislative bills, pamphlets, surveys, photographs, maps, and other items relating to city and industrial planning.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Paul van Tassel Hedden was a city planner.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers consist mainly of correspondence, reports, legislative bills, pamphlets, surveys, photographs, maps, and other items relating to city and industrial planning, particularly in Chicago and Skokie, Illinois and DeKalb County, Georgia; include files relating to the American Institute of Planners (West Great Lakes Chapter), the American Statistical Association, the American Waterway Operators, the Chattahooche Industrial Project, the Chicago Plan Commission, Chicago zoning, the Greater North Michigan Avenue Association, the National Housing Inventory, the National Industrial Zoning Committee, the Regional Science Association, the Skokie Plan Commission, the Urban Land Institute, and the Welfare Council of Metropolitan Chicago.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hedden, Paul van Tassel.; American Institute of Planners. West Great Lakes Chapter.; American Statistical Association.; American Waterway Operators.; Chattahooche Industrial Project.; Chicago Plan Commission.; Greater North Michigan Avenue Association.; National Housing Inventory.; National Industrial Zoning Committee.; Regional Science Association.; Skokie Plan Commission.; Urban Land Institute.; Welfare Council of Metropolitan Chicago.
Subjects:
City planning.; Industries.; Zoning--Illinois--Chicago.; City planners.; Regional science.
Places:
Chicago (Ill.)--City planning.; Skokie (Ill.)--City planning.; DeKalb County (Ga.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Maps.; Photographs.; Surveys.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. General files
Boxes 1-2
Series II. Chicago
Boxes 2-4
Series III. DeKalb County, Georgia
Boxes 4
Series IV. Skokie, Illinois
Boxes 4
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General files
  - Alter Plan (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Institute of Planners, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Institute of Planners, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AIP - Annual Meeting, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AIP - Chapter Sections Committee (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AIP - Chicago Region Chapter, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - AIP - Chicago Region Chapter (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - AIP - Petition, Metropolitan Chicago Section (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AIP - Western Great Lakes Chapter - Meeting Program, Fall 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Planning and Civic Association - National Conference - Miami (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Statistical Association (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Waterways Operators, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Analysis of Zoning Problems (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Boy Scouts - Lincoln Park (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Boy Scouts - Lincoln Park (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Civic Federation Annual Meeting, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Community Planning in Illinois (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Comprehensive Development Plan - City of Griffin and Spalding County (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Forsyth County Road Relocation (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - General (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - General (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - General (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - General X, Y, Z (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - GNMAA - University of Illinois Site. (Greater Northern Michigan Ave. Association) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Harvey Brown (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Illinois Housing Laws (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Lake County, Illinois (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Lincoln Park Conservation Association (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Mutual Insurance Technical Conference (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Map of Evanston, Illinois (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Midnorth Association (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - National Industrial Zoning Committee - through 1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Newspaper Clippings through 1957 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Northbrook Plan Commission (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Planning - Education (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Population (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Regional Science Association (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Series II. Chicago
  - Soil Conservation (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Speech Material (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Tunnard, Christopher - Yale University (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Wauwatosa, Wisconsin (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Urban Land Institute (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Urban Renewal (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Zoning - General (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Zoning Ordinance - DuPage County, Illinois (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chicago Area Transportation Study (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Chicago Better Neighborhood Crusade (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chicago Better Neighborhood Crusade (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chicago - Chicago Heights Industrial Economic Blueprint, c. 1957 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Chicago Metropolitan Area, 1940s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chicago Planning Commission (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Chicago Planning Commission (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Chicago Planning Commission, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chicago Planning Commission - File of Current Major Projects (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chicago Planning Commission - Development, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Chicago Public Schools (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Chicago Regional Port District Board (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Chicago Zoning, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Chicago Zoning, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - City Planning, Department of (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cook County Hospital Improvement (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cook County, Zoning (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cook County, Zoning (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cook County, Zoning (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - General (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - General (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Development Plan - Central Area of Chicago (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Filtration Plant - Proposed Sites (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - First Federal Savings and Loan Association of Chicago (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Greater North Michigan Avenue Association - through 1959 (GNMAA) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - GNMAA - Central Area Plan Review (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - GNMAA - Near North-side Parking Study (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Local Planning Administration (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Housing Construction - Chicago (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Index to Sources of Data, Chicago Metropolitan Area (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Lake Front Ordinance (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Medical Center District (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - National Housing Inventory (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - North Central Area (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Overall Capital Budget Program for Chicago (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Parking - Chicago (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Population and Housing - Chicago (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Population Growth (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Preliminary Metropolitan Planning Report - Chicago (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Public Improvements (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Residential Construction (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Residential Densities (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Residential Land Use of Chicago (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Resources (Pamphlets) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Rezoning - Chicago (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - South Shore, O'Keefe (Oversize) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Urban League (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Welfare Council of Metropolitan Chicago (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Workable Program of the City of Chicago (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Workable Program of the City of Chicago (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Youth Work - Chicago (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Series III. DeKalb County, Georgia
  - Chattahoochee Industrial Project (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - DeKalb County, Georgia (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - DeKalb County, Georgia, Clippings (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - General (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Series IV. Skokie, Illinois
  - Skokie, Building Department (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Skokie, Development (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Skokie, General (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Skokie - Hartung vs. Village of Skokie (Motel Site) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Skokie - Hartung Code Committee (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Skokie - Parking (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Skokie - Parking (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Skokie Plan Commission (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Skokie - Proposal Land Use and Zoning (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Skokie - Searle Parkway (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Skokie, Ill., Zoning (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Skokie, Zoning Supplementary Copies (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Skokie - Zoning Ordinance (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Village of Skokie News Clippings (Box 4, Folder 36)